Armando Marchena

19-11-1988 Rotterdam 06-39187797

<u>marchena.armando@gmail.com</u> https://www.linkedin.com/in/armando-marchena-67908084

I am an all-around Senior Engineer with an affinity for sustainable energy, power distribution and project

management. I have experience in designing and managing projects for local and international dients such as the Port of Rotterdam, Shell, PTTEP, Marathon Oil and Saudi Aramco.

With my strong skills being; accurate and efficient approach to problem solving, planning and organization, communication and coaching, I am capable of leading a team of Engineers to ensure that projects are completed in time and within the agreed upon budget.

Experience

May 2018 - present

Senior Technical Engineer

ORGA BV, Schiedam

As a Senior Technical Engineer at ORGA BV my responsibilities extend to not only;

- Risk assessment and planning impact due to additional client requirements and deviations;
- Coordinating and managing of internal departments and suppliers to ensure deadlines are met;
- Standardizing and optimizing the Engineering process for the Remote Power Solution and Navigational Aids Business sectors according to the LEAN principle;
- Communications process optimization between the various departments (Sales, Project management, Production and Quality control);
- Coaching other Technical Engineers on the application of new techniques, planning and communication (written and verbal);
- Coaching of Secondary Technical Vocational Education students (MBO) and Bachelor in Electrical Engineering students (HBO);

Technical Engineer

ORGA BV, Schiedam

As a Technical Engineer at ORGA BV my responsibilities extend to not only;

- Sizing of Solar and Wind powered battery charging and distribution systems;
- Design of various explosion proof and non-explosion proof systems such as Solar and Wind Powered battery charge controllers, DC and AC distribution boards, Navigational Aids systems, Gas and Fluid analyzers, Portable early warning vibration analyzer for generators/motors (including remote access and monitoring);
- Advising clients on various Explosion and non-Explosion proof matters;
- Optimizing the Engineering process of one of ORGA's main business sectors; the Helideck Identification and Lighting system;

September 2013 – February 2016

Trainee

ORGA BV, Schiedam

As a Trainee at ORGA BV my responsibilities extend to not only;

- Design of safe area systems such as small scale Solar Powered distribution boards and Navigational Aids systems;
- Design and test of a test system for in-house testing of solar powered systems under various operating conditions;

Education

2012 - 2016

Bachelor in Electrical Engineering

Rotterdam University of Applied Science, Rotterdam

Additional courses:

Safetyl for Operational Managers (VCA-VOL)

2007 - 2012

MBO Electrician

Collegio EPI, Aruba

Additional courses:

- Advanced mathematics and physics

Languages

	Written	Oral
English	Good	Good
Dutch	Good	Good
Papiamento	Outstanding	Outstanding
Spanish	Moderate	Moderate

Courses

- IECEx 05 Unit of Competence Ex001 Basic Principles;
- SolidWorks Essentials;
- SolidWorks Assembly Modeling;
- edX ET3034x: Solar Energy;
- Lean six sigma (Internal training ORGA);

Software knowledge

- AutoCAD Electrical;
- Vision (Phase to Phase);
- SolidWorks 3D;
- MultiSim, MATLAB/Simulink;
- EAGLE PCB design
- Microsoft office packages (up to office 365);
- Windows 98 ~ Windows 10;
- Ms Projects Pro;
- Adobe Audition;

Personal activities

rech	Computing
Social	Mentoring
Musical	Drumming
Others	Traveling